Guide to the Richard Nash Gould Research Materials Used in the Publication "The Twentieth Century Project"
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Richard Nash Gould research materials used in the publication "The Twentieth Century Project"
1900-2005
RU 996
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.27
4 boxes, 1 envelope
63692.8
The material consists of a pamphlet entitled The Draft, sheet music, political buttons, photographs, color transparencies, digital images of photographs and album covers and memorabilia used to illustrate Richard Nash Gould's two volume publication on Yale College and the Whiffenpoofs in the twentieth century, titled The Twentieth Century Project. Many of the images are copies from the holdings of the Yale University Library. Also included is a digital copy of the publication.
Gould, Richard Nash
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 49 (YRG 49), Papers and projects on Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were a gift of Richard Nash Gould, 2005, 2012 and 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The material consists of a pamphlet entitled The Draft, sheet music, political buttons, photographs, color transparencies, digital images of photographs and album covers and memorabilia used to illustrate Richard Nash Gould's two volume publication on Yale College and the Whiffenpoofs in the twentieth century, titled The Twentieth Century Project. Many of the images are copies from the holdings of the Yale University Library. Also included is a digital copy of the publication.
See also the project website at http://www.thetwentiethcenturyproject.com/Home.htm
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Born digital; Gould, Richard Nash; Whiffenpoofs (Musical group); Yale College (1887- ) -- History; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- History; Yale University -- Students
- Richard Nash Gould research materials used in the publication The Twentieth Century Project, 1900-2005; Accession 2006-A-100
  - Sheet music, political buttons, and memorabilia (Box 1)
  - Computer files used to create The Twentieth Century Project Volume I, Yale College - Twentieth Century, 2343 computer files (TIFF, PDF, BMP)
    Scope and Contents
    Beginning in 1900 and concluding with the events of 2001, Volume I is a chronological history of Yale College in the 20th century. Using excerpts drawn primarily from contemporary Yale College publications and from writings and books by Yale College graduates, Volume I portrays the day-to-day life and times at Yale College during the last century. Volume I contains 440 pages and includes over 2,500 photographs and graphic images.
  - Computer files used to create The Twentieth Century Project Volume II, Whiffenpoofs - Twentieth Century, 3467 computer files (TIFF, PDF, BMP)
    The Whiffenpoofs are an a capella singing group founded in 1909 by five Yale College undergraduates. Volume II tells their story. In 158 pages, Volume II includes A MUSICAL HISTORY by Charles Henry Buck III '69 with Robert Richards Birge '68, an index of WHIFFENPOOFS from their founding in 1909 to 2004, an index of over 500 Whiffenpoof SONG ARRANGEMENTS, an index of 70 RECORDINGS from 1915 to 2004, plus 134 SONG TRACKS containing over five hours of music selected from those recordings on 4 CDs, and over 2,000 photographs and graphic images.
- Richard Nash Gould research materials used in the publication The Twentieth Century Project, 1906-2003; Accession 2012-A-025
  - Photographs collected and possibly used by Richard N. Gould in his The Twentieth Century Project (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Publication: The Draft: Views From the Yale Community, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Richard Nash Gould research materials used in the publication The Twentieth Century Project, 1942-1999; Accession 2012-A-072; (2 boxes)
  - Whiffenpoofs research materials - book illustrations, digtial image print-outs, and photographs, 1942-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Whiffenpoofs research materials - digital print-outs and photographs, 1955-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Whiffenpoofs research materials - digital print-outs, photographs and correspondence, 1967-1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Whiffenpoofs research materials - digital image print-outs, photographs, correspondence and song lists, 1981-1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Richard Nash Gould research materials used in the publication The Twentieth Century Project, 1901-1999; Accession 2013-A-057
  - Color transparencies, Undated, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Photographs- Ben Cutler, Circa 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs- Whiffenpoofs 90th reunion, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)